Guide to the Records of the Associate Dean of Libraries RG.38.0.2
New York University Archives
Records of the Office of the Associate Dean of Libraries
1962-1999
New York University Archives
New York University. Libraries
RG.38.0.2
7.5 Linear Feet in 6 record cartons and 3 manuscript boxes
This collection contains material associated with the administration of the Associate Dean, including memoranda, reports, meeting minutes, correspondence and other documentation. An additional accession of material includes VHS tapes and audio cassettes of library meetings and events and library publications in addition to the assorted administrative materials. This collection was donated by Associate Dean Nancy Kranich but contains the records and correspondence of her predecessors and the Dean of libraries.
Physical Access
Please note that this collection is stored offsite, and you must contact the repository to schedule access.
Separated Material
The audio visual material that makes up Accession 03-004 Series II: Library Media has been separated from the documents in the collection and stored with the Audio Visual Collection for preservation. The video and audio tapes were given ID numbers ranging from 4223-4271, and 4330. One item from Accession 03-004, Series III: Publications and Reports, a binder containing New-York Historical Society Annual Reports, grant proposals, deaccessioning information and library plans from 1992-1993 was deaccessioned and transferred to New-York Historical Society.
Arrangement
Series I: Correspondence is divided into two subseries according to when the records were accessioned. Both Subseries I: Accession 01-008 and Subseries II: Accession 03-004 are arranged alphabetically by subject/author heading and then chronologically within each subject/author heading.
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains the records of the Associate Dean of Libraries from 1962 to 2002, with most of the materials dating from the 1970s and 1980s. 01-008, initial accession which represents a majority of the materials in the collection, contains chronological files of correspondence and memoranda from the Associate Dean's office.
Accession 03-004 initially contained correspondence, memoranda, reports, publications, VHS tapes and audio cassettes from the Associate Dean's office. The reports and publications from this accession were transferred to the New-York Historical Society and the audio-visual material was separated from the collection and transferred to the Audio Visual Collection for preservation.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Associate Dean of Libraries assists the Dean of Libraries with the daily administration of the New York University Libraries. Organizational charts place the Associate Dean at different positions within the hierarchy of the Division of Libraries at different times.
The earliest Associate Dean is Eugene P. Kennedy, who served from 1971-1973, and whose responsibilities included managing the newly constructed Bobst Library. Nancy Kranich served as Associate Dean from 1992-2001 before assuming the presidency of the American Library Association.
Access Restrictions
Administrative records and unpublished reports of New York University are closed for a period of 20 years from the date of their creation. Access to files spanning multiple years will be opened to researchers based on the date of the most recent materials. Board of Trustees records are closed for 35 years from the date of creation. Materials related to personnel, grievances, job and fellowship searches and applications, and all files that fall under the federal Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) are permanently restricted. Additional restrictions may apply to other materials in this collection. For questions regarding specific restrictions, please contact the University Archives.
Provenance
Some of these materials were transferred from the Office of the Dean of the Libraries in 1987. Other files were transferred at a later date and make up accession 01-008.
Accession 03-004 was added to this collection in June 2009.
Correspondence.; Memorandums.; Records (documents); Universities and Colleges -- Administration; Elmer Holmes Bobst Library; New York University. Faculty of Arts and Science; New York University. Libraries
- Series I: Correspondence
  - Subseries I: Accession 01-007
    - Memos, 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      General note
      bar code #: 3 1142 04227138 0
    - Department and Unit Head Meeting Minutes, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Department and Unit Head Meeting Minutes, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Library Faculty Council, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Faculty Meetings, 1981-1985 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Dean's Council Members, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Material for Dean's Executive Committee Meeting, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Dedication Press Articles, 1972-1979 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Elmer H. Bobst Memorial Service, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Bobst Memorial Services, Correspondence, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Building and Planning Annual Reports, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Bobst Book Clubs, 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - E. H. Bobst-Bust Relocation, 1966-1973 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Bobst Library Dedication Correspondence, 1970-1979 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Bobcat Press Conference, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Bobst Background, 1962-1983 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Bobst Background, 1962-1983 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Grants Available, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Administrative Staff Meetings, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Special Collections, 1976-1981 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Spanish Collections, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - United Nations Collection, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Chrono, February 27-28, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Chrono, March-May 1978 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Chrono, June 1978 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Chrono, July-August 1978 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Chrono, September 1978 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Chrono, October-November 1978 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Chrono, December 1978 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Chrono, January-February 1979 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Chrono, March-April 1979 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Chrono, May 1979 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Chrono, June-August 1979 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Chrono, September-October 1979 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Chrono, November 1979 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Chrono, December 1979-January 1980, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Chrono, February 1980 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      bar code #: 3 1142 04227139 8
    - Chrono, March-April 1980 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Chrono, May 1980 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Chrono, June-July 1980 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Chrono, August 1980 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Chrono, September-November 1980 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Chrono, December 1980 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Chrono, January-February 1981 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Chrono, March 1981 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Chrono, April-May 1981 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Chrono, June 1981 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Chrono, July 1981 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Chrono, September-November 1981 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Chrono, December 1981-February 1982, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Chrono, March-June 1982, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Chrono, July-October 1982 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Chrono, January-April 1986 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Chrono, May-July 1986 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Chrono, July-November 1986 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Chrono, November 1986-January 1987, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Chrono, February-May 1987 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Chrono, May-July 1987 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Chrono, July-November 1987 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Chrono, December 1987- January 1988, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Chrono, February-March 1988 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Chrono, March-May 1988 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      bar code #: 3 1142 04227140 6
    - Chrono, June-August 1988 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Chrono, September-November 1988 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Chrono, December 1988 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Chrono, January-April 1989 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Travel Expenses-Rochell, Carlton, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Dr. Alex Lacey/Dallas, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - NYU Library Consortium, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - University of Texas-Dallas, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Tulane, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - NOTIS Customers, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Direct/NYU, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
      bar code #: 3 1142 04227140 60
    - Voice/Video, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Description and Specs: VTS, Video, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - NMSU (New Mexico State University), 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Telephone Renewal, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Bibliotheque de France Project with Richard Meier & Partners, 1985-1989 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Douglas County Library System (Oregon), 1987 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Dean Rochell's Chrono File, January 1997 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Dean Rochell's Chrono File, February 1997 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Dean Rochell's Chrono File, March 1997 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Dean Rochell's Chrono File, April-May 1997, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Dean Rochell's Chrono File, June-July 1997 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Dean Rochell's Chrono File, August-October 1997 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Dean Rochell's Chrono File, November 1997-January 1998, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Dean Rochell's Chrono File, February-March 1998 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Dean Rochell's Chrono File, April-May 1998 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      bar code #: 3 1142 04227582 9
    - Dean Rochell's Chrono File, June-July 1998 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Dean Rochell's Chrono File, August-December 1998 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Dean Rochell's Chrono File, January-March 1999 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Subseries II: Accession 03-004
    - Acquisitions Reports, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      bar code #: 3 1142 04227141 4
    - Administration Policies & Procedures, 1975-1983 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Administration Policies & Procedures, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Advisory Board Committee - Center New Media Info Tech, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - 15th Anniversary, Bobst Library, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Atrium, Use Of, 1976-1994 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Asbestos Control, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Audio Visual Committee, 1985-1990 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Audio Visual Committee, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Audio Visual Committee, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Avery Fisher Center for Music & Media, 1984-1987 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Avery Fisher Center Correspondence, 1990-1992 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Avery Fisher Center - Use of Presentation Rooms, 1986-1990 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Bobcat Instruction Taskforce, 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Bobcat's Den, 1987-1998 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Bobst Brochures, 1973-1981 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Bobst Brochures, 1982-1994 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Cable for Faculty Housing, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Cable Service to Dorms, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Cable Service to Dorms, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Cable Service to Dorms, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Campus Media General Correspondence, 1992-1996 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Campus Media Support SVCS Correspondence, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Campus Media/VPC, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Campus Media Support Services/Problem Diamond/West, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Campus Media Support Services/Problem Diamond/West, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Cataloging - Research Library Information Center Ballots, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Cataloging - Annual Reports, 1975-1986 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Chelsea House, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Chronological Files at Archives, 1989-1993 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Circulation Fines, 1972-1982 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Circulation - General Correspondence, 1972-1993 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      bar code #: 3 1142 04227142 2
    - Circulation - CLSI, 1974-1981 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Circulation - Annual Reports, 1978-1986 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - C Media/ Dymaxion, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Coles Science Library Annual Reports, 1980-1986 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Collection Development Annual Reports, 1976-1991 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Complaints, 1968-1975 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Complaints, 1976-1986 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Complaints, 1987-1991 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Complaints, 1992-1995 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Complaints, 1992-1993 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Compliments, 1971-1996 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Consortium, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Consortium, 1979-1984 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Consortium, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Consortium, 1972-1976 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Consultants Information & Reports, 1969-1990 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Cost Function Study Tantalus, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Cost Allocation/ Library, 1991-1993 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Department & Unit Head Meeting, 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Department & Unit Head Meeting, 1988-1989 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Department & Unit Head Meeting, 1989-1991 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Department Review, Bobst, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Department Review, Bobst, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Disabled Student Services, 1990-1991 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      bar code #: 3 1142 04227143 0
    - Dissertations, 1986-1990 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Dissertations, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Documents/UN, 1956-1981 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Documents/US Government, 1972-1995 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - ERC/ Laptop Computers, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Exhibits Committee, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Exhibits, 1973-1987 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Five Year Plan, 1972-1977 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Five Year Plan Revisions, 1986-1990 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Five Year Plan Masters, 1987-1992 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Floor Plans, Bobst, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - GBA Library - Correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - GBA Library - Correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - GBA Library - Correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - GBA Library - Annual Reports, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Hazard Communication Program, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - HEGIS - Statistics, 1987-1993 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Herald Tribune Morgue, 1967-1983 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Library Hours, 1967-1968 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Library Hours, 1972-1973 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Library Hours, 1974-1980 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Library Hours, 1981-1996 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - IAIMS, undated (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Institute for Economic Analysis, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - IFA: Space, 1994-1997 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - IFA: Space, 1990-1993 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - IFA Library - Annual Reports, 1974-1989 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - IMC - Expansion Plan Expenditures, 1976-1977 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - IMC - Learning Resource Center Proposal, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      bar code #: 3 1142 04227583 7
    - IMC - Annual Reports, 1980-1984 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - IMC - Radio Shack Proposal, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - IMC - Past Plans & Proposed Expansion, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Infrastructure Comm., 1993 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - "In Praise of Libraries & Librarians", 1988 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Instructional Materials Center, 1969-1975 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Instructional Media Center - General Correspondence, 1973-1983 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Integrated Information Service System, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Law Library - Correspondence, 1971-1975 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Law Library - Correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Law Library - Correspondence, 1978-1984 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Librarians' Statement (against Dean Kennedy), 1975 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Libraries of NYU, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      bar code #: 3 1142 04227584 5
    - Maintenance, 1973-1980 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Microfilm Project, 1972-1984 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Microcomputer Software Committee, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Microcomputer Center, 1989-1993 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Medical Library, 1971-1997 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - "The Story of NYU" NY Times reprint, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Special Collections at Bobst, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - NYU Libraries Automation Planning Reports, October 1993 (Box 9, Object 9)
    - NYU Center for Digital Multimedia Production, Publishing & Education, 1993-1994 Application for Funding (Box 9, Object 10)